Guide to the Stanford University Video Collection SC1031
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University video collection
1934-2016
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University
SC1031
533 item(s)
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Videorecordings.; Stanford University -- History.; Stanford University
- Videos
  - Donald Kennedy inauguration, parts 1-4, 1980; V001; 4 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Stanford University -- Presidents.; Kennedy, Donald.
  - Paul Berg press conference: Nobel Prize, 1980; V002; 1 videotape(s)
    Nobel prize -- Stanford faculty -- Biochemistry; Berg, Paul
  - Emile Holman interview by Dr. Robert A. Chase, 1980 Jul; V003; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Medical faculty -- S.U. Medical School; Holman, Emile; Chase, Robert A.
  - Caspar Weinberger at Stanford, 1982 Mar 12; V004; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Weinberger, Caspar
  - Three Mile Island report, 1979 Mar 30; V005; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Stephens, Mark; Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant (Pa.)
  - Arthur Schawlow press conference: Nobel Prize, 1981 Oct; V006.1; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Stanford University -- Faculty.; Nobel prize; Schawlow, Arthur; Laser physics
  - Arthur Schawlow press conference: Nobel Prize, 1981 Oct; V006.2; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Nobel prize; Laser physics; Schawlow, Arthur; Stanford University -- Faculty.
  - Ansel Adams and Wallace Stegner, a conversation, 1982; V007; 4 videotape(s)
    Stegner, Wallace; Adams, Ansel; Nature conservation.
  - From Maser to Laser, a talk by Arthur Schawlow at Lawrence Livermore Lab, 1982; V008; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford University -- Faculty.; Schawlow, Arthur; Physics.
  - Hackers, 1985; V009; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Computer industry.; Silicon Valley
  - Portrait of a Pioneer: Fred Terman, 1984; V010; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Electronic industries.; Hewlett-Packard Company; Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-1982
  - Silicon Valley: Company Town; Boom Town, 1986; V011; 3 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Moline, Julio; Computer industry.; Computers.; Silicon Valley
  - Knowledge Engineering: Artificial Intelligence Research at Stanford, 1985; V012; 2 videotape(s)
    Heuristic Programming Project; Feigenbaum, Edward A.; Artificial intelligence.
  - Walter Mondale rally at Stanford, part 1 and 2, 1984 Oct 16; V013; 7 videotape(s); 7 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Mondale, Walter; Politics; Presidential elections; Hart, Gary
  - Grand Design: a history of the Stanford Museum, 1986; V014; 2 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Museums.; Williams, Roger; Osborne, Carol
  - Stanford Experience, 1983; V015; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Walter G. Vincenti at Stanford, 1985 May 12; V016; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Vincenti, Walter G.
  - Stanford today, 1985; V017; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Jane Stanford and the idea of a university [videorecording and typed transcript], 1987; V018; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford University -- History.; Ryan, Patricia L
  - Steven Mosher on 60 Minutes, 1983 Jun; V019; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Mosher, Steven; China; Academic freedom; Students
  - Stanford Heritage: A Centennial Perspective, V020; 3 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford centennial; Stanford University -- History.
  - Cancer, a documentary with Kaplan interview, 1971; V021; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Cancer.; Kaplan, Henry
  - Up Towards Mountains Higher, 1987; V022.1; 6 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Students -- Academics; Stanford University -- History.
  - Up Towards Mountains Higher, 1987; V022.2; 1 videotape(s) (1 inch)
  - Up Towards Mountains Higher, 1987; V022.3; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Stanford University -- History.; Students -- Academics
  - Astrophysicist, V023; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Astrophysics
  - Physicists at Work, V024; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Physics.
  - Silicon Run, 1986; V025; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Carranza, Ruth A.; Microelectronics industry.; Center for Integrated Systems; Silicon Valley
  - Mice, windows, and the great comet; lecture by Alan Kay at MacFest; parts 1 and 2, 1985 May 20; V026; 2 videotape(s) (u-matic); 2 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Computer engineering; Kay, Alan; Stanford Macintosh Users' Group
  - Uncommon man dinner, 1987 May 15; V027; 5 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford Associates; Hewlett, William R.; Arnot, Peter.; Menzinger, Peggy.; Packard, David, 1912-1996; Packard, David W.; Packard, Lucile
  - Meetings on racism, Stanford, 1987; V028; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Students -- racism
  - Center for the Study of Language and Information, V029; 2 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Let's Look at Stanford, circa 1964 or 1955-59; V030; 2 videotape(s)
    Students; Stanford University -- Campus scenes; Stanford University -- Buildings.; Lehman, Matt; Football -- big game
  - President Sterling's inauguration, 1949 Oct 7; V031; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Stanford University -- Presidents.; Johnson, Paul C.; Sterling, J. E. Wallace; Stanford University -- Buildings.
  - Stanford in Wartime, circa 1944; V032; 3 videotape(s)
  - Shape of the Future, circa 1955; V033; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Scientific research; Jones, William O.; Faculty; Lederberg, Joshua; Students; Stanford University -- Construction; Stanford University -- Campus scenes
  - Big Game, 1952, V034; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Scope and Contents
    Approximately 10 minutes of footage from the 3rd quarter of the 1952 Big Game. Berkeley beat Stanford 26-0. The remaining 20 minutes of the video are blank.
    Stanford University -- Athletics
  - Stanford in Autumn, 1948; V035; 3 videotape(s)
    Spaeth, Carl B.; Stanford University -- Construction; Students; Football -- big game; Edwards, Paul; Crothers, George; Eurich, Alvin; Stanford University -- Crothers Hall dedication
  - Stanford: A Sentimental Journey, 1987; V036.1; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Alumni; Faculty; Stanford University -- History.
  - Stanford: A Sentimental Journey, 1987; V036.2; 1 videotape(s); videotapes (1 inch)
    Stanford University -- History.; Alumni; Faculty
  - Stanford: A Sentimental Journey, 1987; V036.3; 5 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford University -- History.; Faculty; Alumni
  - Stanford: a Sentimental Journey, 1987; V036WD.1; 105 videotape(s) (betacam)
    Faculty; Alumni; Stanford University -- History.
  - Stanford: a Sentimental Journey, 1987; V036WD.2; 16 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Cornerstone: Making History Again, 1987; V037.1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Shultz, George; Students; Sepulveda, Bernardo>; Kennedy, Donald.; Stanford centennial
  - Cornerstone: Making History Again, 1987; V037.2; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Stanford centennial; Shultz, George; Students; Sepulveda, Bernardo>; Kennedy, Donald.
  - Cornerstone: Making History Again, 1987; V037.3; videotapes (1 inch)
    Kennedy, Donald.; Stanford centennial; Sepulveda, Bernardo>; Students; Shultz, George
  - Cornerstone: Making History Again, 1987; V037.4; 21 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Cornerstone: Making History Again, 1987; V037WD.1; 11 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Students; Stanford centennial; Shultz, George; Kennedy, Donald.; Sepulveda, Bernardo>
  - Cornerstone: Making History Again, 1987; V037WD.2; 65 videotape(s) (betacam)
    Shultz, George; Stanford centennial; Sepulveda, Bernardo>; Kennedy, Donald.; Students
  - SRI: The Founding Years - Part 1 and Part 2, 1983; V038; 8 videotape(s); 2 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Stanford Research Institute; Gibson, Weldon B.; Faculty; Athletics; Arbuckle, Ernest C.
  - Sterling Memorial Service, 1985 Jul 9; V039; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Sterling, J. E. Wallace; Stanford University -- Presidents.
  - Edward Feigenbaum: Towards a Science of Scientific Thought. Parts 1, 2, 3, 1976 Sep 30; V040; 3 videotape(s) (1 inch); videotapes (Reel)
    Science; Feigenbaum, Edward A.; Faculty; Computer science.
  - SDI Video Project. edited master, 1987; V041.1; videotapes (1 inch)
    Strategic Defense Initiative.; Kennedy, Donald.; Harris, John; Drell, Sidney; Madley, John C.; Military research.; Winograd, Terry; McCarthy, John; Faculty
  - SDI Video Project. Madley interview, 1987; V041.2; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Madley, John C.; Strategic Defense Initiative.; Faculty; Military research.
  - SDI Video Project. First taping, 1987 May 27; V041.3; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Strategic Defense Initiative.; Military research.; Faculty
  - SDI Video Project. Panel of graduate students, 1987 May 28; V041.4; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Strategic Defense Initiative.; Faculty; Military research.
  - SDI Video Project. Interviews with McCarthy and Winograd, 1987 Aug 7; V041.5; 2 videotape(s)
    Military research.; Faculty; Strategic Defense Initiative.; McCarthy, John; Winograd, Terry
  - SDI Video Project. Interviews with McCarthy and Winograd, 1987 Aug 7; V041.5b; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - SDI Video Project. Interviews with Kennedy and Harris, 1987 AUg 7; V041.6; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Harris, John; Strategic Defense Initiative.; Military research.; Faculty; Kennedy, Donald.
  - SDI Video Project. Interview with Sid Drell, 1987 Aug 7; V041.7; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Strategic Defense Initiative.; Military research.; Drell, Sidney; Faculty
  - Speaking of Stanford, V042; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Public Relations.
  - Storey family scenes: Parnie Storey [Snoke] graduation from medical school and wedding, 1934; V043; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Students; Hopkins, Timothy; Medical School; Commencement; Wilbur, Ray Lyman.; Hoover, Herbert; Storey, Parnie
  - Hearts and Quarks, 1988; V044; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Drell, Sidney; Shumway, Norman; Surgeons; Faculty; Physicists.
  - Computer Science at Stanford; the impact of the first ten years, 1987 Mar 27; V045; 12 videotape(s)
    Artificial intelligence.; Faculty; Computer industry.; McCarthy, John, 1927-2011; Knuth, Donald Ervin, 1938-; Feigenbaum, Edward A.
  - Felix Bloch symposium, 1989 Oct 27-28; V052; 9 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Bloch, Felix
  - Foundations of Measurement: lectures, 1978; V053; 8 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Measure theory.; Luce, R. Duncan; Faculty
  - The California Bay Area earthquake symposium at Stanford University, 1989 Oct 26; V054.1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Kiremidjian, Anne; Krawinkler, Helmut; Shah, Haresh; earthquake 1989
  - Stanford University earthquake damage, 1989 Oct 19; V054.2; 2 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Museums.; Stanford University -- Anatomy building; earthquake 1989; Libraries.; Stanford University -- Geology corner; Stanford University -- Encina Hall
  - Stanford University earthquake damage and SITN classroom footage, 1989 Oct 17; V054.3; 3 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford University -- Geology corner; Stanford University -- Encina Hall; Stanford University -- Anatomy building; Museums.; earthquake 1989; Libraries.
  - Western Culture Faculty Symposium, 1980-1981; V055; 18 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Faculty; Western culture
  - Gays and Lesbians in the residences, 1986; V056; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Lesbianism.; Homosexuality.; Students; Student housing.; Residential education
  - Memoirs of an Engineer; a biography of Carl Breer, 1990?; V057; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Breer, Carl; Automobiles; Students; Class of 1909; Engineering.; Chrysler Corporation
  - To Touch History: Gorbachev at Stanford, 1990; V059; 2 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Shultz, George Pratt; Kennedy, Donald.; Gorbachev, Mikhail
  - Success Story: Stanford University electronics and research lab, 1990; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Computer films - Soviet Ant Takes a Walk; Programmable Assembly; and others, 1970s; V061; 2 videotape(s) (u-matic); 2 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Computer science.
  - Stanford Centennial Convocation (news programs on protest), 1991 Oct 1; V063; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford centennial; Political protests; Gay rights; Wilson, Pete
  - Founders' Day ceremony, 1991 Mar 10; V064; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Anna M. Chavez; Founders Day; Wallace Stegner; Richard W. Lyman; Stanford centennial
  - Janet Lewis reading at Stanford, 1990 Nov 5; V065; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    American literature.; Creative Writing Program; Lewis, Janet
  - Orientation faculty debates: should we have manned space flight, 1986 Sep; V066.1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Residential education; Faculty; space flight
  - Orientation faculty debates: is third world poverty America's fault, 1986 Sep; V066.2; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Developing countries; poverty; Residential education; Faculty
  - Orientation faculty debates: has Christianity been a good thing for western culture, 1986 Sep; V066.3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Faculty; Residential education; Christianity
  - Orientation faculty debates: reading works of western culture, a critical approach, 1986 Sep; V066.4; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Faculty; Residential education; Western culture
  - Grace Paley: artist-in-residence (a reading), 1987 Feb 17; V067; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Paley, Grace; American literature.; Residential education
  - Stanford in Autumn (1948)--Let's Look at Stanford, circa 1964; V068
  - Great moments of the big game, 1991; V069; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Champions: A century of Stanford sports, 1991; V070; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Athletics; Murphy, Bob.; Walsh, Bill,; Luisetti, Hank.; Mathias, Bob, 1930; Rose Bowl; Women's basketball
  - Gerhard Casper inauguration, 1992 Oct 2; V071; 3 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Casper, Gerhard.; Stanford University -- Presidents.
  - Stanford centennial roundtables, 1991; V072; 8 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford centennial
  - Tribute to Wallace Stegner, 1993 Mar 26; V073; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Moffat, Mary Jane.; Packer, Nancy Huddleston.; Painter, Charlotte.; Raskell, Judith.; Wilrich, Patricia.; Young, Al.; Zelder, Patricia; Faculty; American literature.; Stegner, Wallace; Hansen, Ron.; Houston, James D.; Long, Sam.
  - Stanford Football, California at Stanford, Game #11, 1991 Nov 23; V074; 2 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Martin Luther King program at Memorial Church, 1994; V075; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    African Americans; Thompkins, Floyd; Martin Luther King, Jr. Papers Project; Casper, Gerhard.; Massey, Tom.; Rice, Condoleezza; Carson, Clayborne, 1944-
  - Korea/Vietnam Memorial plaques dedication, 1989 May 29; V076; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Veterans; war memorials
  - Tresidder Memorial Union, circa 1990; V077; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Students; staff; Tresidder Memorial Union; Bird, Amy
  - Stanford Alumni Association master tapes, 1985-1993; V078
  - Origins of Modern Society, 1989; V079; 17 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Lectures.; Almond, Gabriel Abraham; Western culture; Faculty; Emmons, Terence.; Evans, J. Martin (John Martin), 1935; Chace, William; Craig, Gordon Alexander, 1913; Lougee, Carolyn.; Vincenti, Walter G.; Kennedy, David M.; Solomon, Ezra.; Jameson, Michael.; Guerard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph), 1914-; Raubitschek, A.E. (Antony Erich), 1912; Ratner, Leonard G.; Sheehan, James J.; Perry, John.; Ryan, Lawrence.
  - Stanford - The True Source of Knowledge, 1965; V080; 3 videotape(s)
    Project South.; Rubbo, Michael; Political protests; Students; Faculty
  - John Elway; fundamentals of offensive football, 1987; V081; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
  - Vaclav Havel accepting Ralston Prize, 1994; V082; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Ralston Prize; Baez, Joan; Brest, John; Havel, Vaclav; Law School
  - Century of Women, Part 1, 2, 3, 1994; V083; 4 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Mosher, Clelia; Women.; Freedman, Estelle
  - In the Game, 1994; V084; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    VanDerveer, Tara; Women's basketball; Whiting, Val; Henning, Sonja; Stevens, Trisha; Steding, Katy; Azzi, Jennifer; Athletics
  - Empire Builders, 1993; V085; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Stanford University -- History.; Central Pacific Railroad; Big Four
  - Palm Drive TV Spot, 1994 Jul 12; V086; 2 videotape(s); 2 videotapes (VHS; Beta)
    Kimball, Margaret; Palm Drive; Campus roads
  - Robinson, Louis G. Tapes from first AAAI conference, Stanford, 1980; 26 videotape(s)
    Computers.; American Association for Artificial Intelligence
  - Good and Evil, 1993; V087; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Smith, Robert J; Nunziato, Elizabeth; Human nature; civil rights movement; Good and evil; Foard, James Harlan; Ivanhoe, P.J.; Young, Erne W.D.; Bach, Alice; Cordell, LaDoris H.; Yearley, Lee H.; Bielefeldt, Carl; Carson, Clayborne, 1944-
  - S.U. Centennial - Postal Ceremony, 1990; V088; 3 videotape(s) (vhs)
    centennial
  - Gorbachev visit, 1990 Jun 4; V089; 22 videotape(s)
    Kennedy, Donald.; Gorbachev, Mikhail
  - Gorbachev visit, 1992 May 8; V090; 2 videotape(s) (mii)
    Gorbachev, Mikhail
  - House Committee Hearings, Stanford indirect cost rate, 1990?; V091; 7 videotape(s) (mii)
    indirect cost
  - 20/20 Interview of Don Kennedy; indirect costs rate, 1990?; V092; 1 videotape(s) (mii)
    indirect cost; Kennedy, Donald.
  - Success Story: Stanford Univ. Electronics and Research Lab, 1954 May 18; V093.1; 1 videotape(s) (betacam)
    Electronics; Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-1982; Varian, Russell Harrison; Packard, David, 1912-1996; Chodorow, Marvin; Harris, Donald Brewer.; Hewlett, William R.
  - Success Story: Stanford Univ. Electronics and Research Lab, 1954 May 18; V093.2; 1 videotape(s) (betacam)
    Electronics; Hewlett, William R.; Harris, Donald Brewer.; Chodorow, Marvin; Packard, David, 1912-1996; Terman, Frederick Emmons, 1900-1982; Varian, Russell Harrison
  - Stanford Humanities Center Presents Allen Ginsberg, 1995 Feb 10; V094; 6 videotape(s)
    Stanford Humanities Center; Literature; Ginsberg, Allen
  - Service of Thanksgiving for Stanford's 100 Years, 1991 Oct 1; V095; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    centennial; Gregg, Robert
  - Centennial Convocation, 1991 Oct 1; V096; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Wilson, Pete; Stanford University -- centennial
  - Zapata Murals, 1994 Aug 31; V097; 2 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Casa Zapata; Burciaga, Tony; Chicano art
  - H-P Project: Founders of the Future, 1995; V098; 30 videotape(s)
    Packard, David; Electronics -- Research.; Linvill, John; Guerard, Albert J. (Albert Joseph), 1914-; McConnell, Susan; Silicon Valley; Bing, Peter; Hewlett, William R.
  - Bing project, 1993-1994; V099; 13 videotape(s)
    Lyman, Richard W.; VanDerveer, Tara; Brennan, Frank; Henning, Sonja; Doyle, Morris; Freidenrich, John; Kennedy, Donald.; Bloem, K; Swezy, M; Bing, Peter; Meier, Linda; Jackson, Shawna
  - Stanford University centennial spots, 1990; V100; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    centennial; Brokaw, Tom; Oliveira, Nathan; Public Relations.
  - Jesse Jackson, Martin Luther King, Jr. birthday celebration, 1987; V101; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Jackson, Jesse; Phillips, Steve; Gould, William; Black Students Union
  - Short briefing for President Mitterand prior to his visit, 1984 Mar 26; V102; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Chowning, John M.; computer research in acoustics; robotics research; research and industry; Robertson, Channing; Binford, Tom; Kennedy, Donald.
  - Conference with President Francois Mitterand at the Center for Integrated Systems, 1984 Mar 26; V103; 1 videotape(s) (vhs)
    Research; Technology; Center for Integrated Systems; Morgenthaler, David; Burton, McMurtry; Meindl, James; Feigenbaum, Edward A.; Gibbons, James; Noyce, Robert; Kennedy, Donald.; Young, John; Berg, Paul; Perkins, Thomas J.; Mitterand, Francois; Amdahl, Gene M. (Gene Myron), 1922-2015; Jobs, Steve, 1955-2011
  - ASSU Speakers Bureau presents Nicholas Daniloff, 1986 Nov 20; V104; 4 videotape(s) (3 U-Matic, 1 VHS); 3 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Daniloff, Nicholas; U.S. Soviet relations
  - Craig pilot, V105; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
  - Queen Elizabeth II's visit, 1983 Mar 3; V106; 4 videotape(s) (u-matic); 4 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Queen Elizabeth; distinguished visitors
  - Coretta Scott King at Stanford University, 1986 Nov 6; V107; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Coretta Scott King, visiting the Martin Luther King, Jr. Papers Project at Stanford University in November, spoke on ending apartheid in South Africa.
    South Africa.; Apartheid; King, Coretta Scott
  - Great Powers Seminar: the United States, 1982 Apr 18; V108; 2 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Corn, Wanda; Chace, William; Lyman, Richard W.; Zelditch, Morris; American literature.; arts and humanities
  - Pamela Djerassi bisiting artist: Barbara Ross Greenberg, 1981 Aug 14; V109; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Art.; Greenberg, Barbara Ross
  - Visit by Li Peng, Vice-Premier of China, 1981 Aug 14; V110; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Peng, Li; Center for Integrated Systems; Silicon Valley; distinguished visitors
  - Forsythe Lecture Series: Ronald Rivest, 1984 Jan 25; V111; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    Rivest, Ronald; Computer science.
  - Shirley Chisholm lecture on Martin Luther King, Jr. birthday, 1985 Jan 15; V112; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)
    South Africa.; Chisholm, Shirley; King, Martin Luther
  - Bishop Desmond Tutu at Stanford, 1986-01-21; V113; 7 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Tutu, Desmond; South Africa.; Apartheid; Martin Luther King Jr. Birthday; Carson, Clayborne, 1944-
  - Superconductivity, 1988 Nov-Dec; V114; 7 videotape(s); 7 videotapes (.75 inch)
    Biographical/Historical note
    Theodore Geballe was professor of Applied Physics and Materials Science Engineering at Stanford University.
    Three tapes from an interview with Theodore Geballe on superconductivity, November 1988; and four tapes on superconductivity, December 1988, including a levitation experiment, crystal growth, and a meeting.
    Physics.; Geballe, Theodore
  - The Jericho Fault, 1989; V115; 7 videotape(s)
    Video tapes on Amos Nur's research on the Jericho fault, which crosses through Israel, Jordan, and Syria. Includes five source tapes and two edited masters.
    Earthquakes.; Nur, Amos; Davis, Doug
  - University in Society: Do the Ties Bind, 1969; V116; 3 videotape(s)
    Footage was shot in 1969 and concerns student demonstrations on campus, especially against the military research undertaken at Stanford, and administrative responses to student activism; also included is a campus meeting concerning the Study of Education at Stanford. Individuals featured include Kenneth Pitzer, university president, Richard Lyman, provost, Herbert Packer, vice provost, Willard Wyman Jr., dean of students, and faculty members William Rambo, Raymond Wolfinger, Richard Brody, and Richard Fagan. The students were not identified by name. This film was made as part of a PBS series on American universities; Don Lenzer was the director for this episode on Stanford.
    Related Archival Materials note
    Original 16mm film housed in: Film Collection, Dept. of Special Collections, Stanford University Libraries.
    Wyman, Willard; Packer, Herbert; Lyman, Richard W.; Pitzer, Kenneth; Rambo, William; Siegel, Lenny; SRI; Student demonstrations.
  - Stanford vs. USC, 1968; V117; 3 videotape(s)
  - Poetry reading by Robert Creeley, in the company of Robert Grenier and Leslie Scalapino, 1993 Oct 21; V118; 4 videotape(s)
    This event was sponsored by the Stanford University Department of English and the Creative Writing Program; Creeley was on campus as part of the celebration of the 6 millionth acquisition of the Stanford University Libraries, represented by the papers of Robert Creeley. Collection includes two master tapes and a viewing copy on VHS. Stanford, CA: Stanford Instructional Television Network, 1993.
    Creeley, Robert; Grenier, Robert; Scalapino, Leslie
  - A conversation with Robert Creeley; with Marjorie Perloff, Albert Gelpi, and Gilbert Sorrentino, 1993 Oct 22; V119; 3 videotape(s)
    This event, on October 22, 1993, was part of the celebration of the 6 millionth acquisition of the Stanford University Libraries, represented by the papers of Robert Creeley. Included are two source tapes and one VHS viewing copy.
    Creeley, Robert; Perloff, Marjorie; Gelpi, Albert; Sorrentino, Gilbert
  - SITN guest lecture series, 1986; V120; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic)